<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The address of the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Common-Council of the city of London, to the Lords spiritual and temporal in Parliament with the answer thereunto, delivered by the Lord Marquis of Halifax, Lord Privy-Seal, and Speaker of the House of Lords.</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A70483</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2859C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R179962</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12406254</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12406254</idno>
            <idno type="VID">61400</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A70483)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 61400)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1637:40, 767:49)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The address of the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Common-Council of the city of London, to the Lords spiritual and temporal in Parliament with the answer thereunto, delivered by the Lord Marquis of Halifax, Lord Privy-Seal, and Speaker of the House of Lords.</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Lords.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by James Partridge, Matthew Gillyflower, and Samuel Heyrick ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1688/9 [i.e. 1689]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>The address, in support of William, is dated March 8, 1688, and is countersigned "by order of Common-Council". The reply and order to print are both dated 12 March 1688.</note>
                  <note>This item appears at reel 767:49 as Wing L2868 (number cancelled in Wing 2nd ed.) and at reel 1637:40 as Wing L2859C.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>William --  III, --  King of England, 1650-1702.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Revolution of 1688.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>Sarah Wingo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>Sarah Wingo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="address">
            <pb facs="tcp:61400:1"/>
            <head>THE ADDRESS OF THE LORD MAYOR, ALDERMEN, and COMMON-COUNCIL OF THE City of London, TO THE LORDS SPIRITUAL and TEMPORAL IN PARLIAMENT: With the ANSWER thereunto, Delivered by the Lord Marquis of <hi>HALIFAX,</hi> Lord Privy-Seal, and Speaker of the Houſe of Lords.</head>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>To the Right Honourable, the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, in PARLIAMENT Aſſembled.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>E the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Commons of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> in Common-Council Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled, preſume to Addreſs our ſelves to this Honourable Houſe; with our moſt humble Thanks for your excellent Conduct of Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs in this time of our great Exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gency and Extremity, when our Lives, our Religion, and our Eſtates were ſo eminently threatned; And eſpecially for your Addreſs to His
<pb facs="tcp:61400:2"/>MAJESTY the 5th Inſtant; declaring your Reſolu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to Aſſiſt, and ſtand by His MAJESTY, in Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porting His Allies Abroad, in Reducing <hi>Ireland,</hi> and in De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of the Proteſtant Religion and Laws of this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom.</p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>
                     <date>
                        <hi>March</hi> 8. 1688.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>By Order of Common-Council,</hi> Wagſtaff.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>Die Martis <hi>12<hi rend="sup">o</hi>
                  </hi> Martii. <hi>1688.</hi>
               </head>
               <opener>
                  <salute>Mr. Recorder,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>THE Lords receive very kindly the Addreſs you have made to them: And as they are glad to find that the City of <hi>London</hi> is well pleaſed with what they have done for the Publick Service; ſo you may be aſſured, That they will ſtill purſue the ſame Ends, and uſe the beſt Methods for the Security of the Proteſtant Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion, and for the Peace and Settlement of the Nation.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <head>Die Martis, 12<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Martii. 1688.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>ORdered by the Lords Spiritual and Temporal in Parliament Aſſembled, That the Addreſs of the Lord Mayor, Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and Commons of the City of</hi> London <hi>preſented to the Houſe this day, and the Anſwer of this Houſe thereunto, be forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with Printed and Publiſhed.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Jo. Brown, <hi>Cler. Parliamentorum.</hi>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>Iames Partridge, Matthew Gillyflower,</hi> and <hi>Samuel Heyrich,</hi> Printers to the Houſe of Lords. 1688/9.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:61400:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
